Guide to the Felix Adler Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Classified Papers
  - Subseries II.1: Columbia Lectures (100)
    - Main Problems of Ethics, 1917 September-1918 February 8 (Box 28)
      (The War situation (Butler and Lafollette) The problem of Aristotle, Plato, Christianity, Buddha, Our prob1em - Worth, Personality, etc. Extra beliefs vs. Ethical Experience. Freedom of speech in University and Church. Attitude toward Germany discussed. Mill’s Utilitarianism. Ethics distinguished from morals. "Loyalty” -Royce, James- Moral Equivalents of War. The Pragmatic position. Dewey and 'Tufts “Moral Theory". National Unity. Interdependence and spiritual, universe. Origen and origin of evil. Types of evil.)
    - Main Problems of Ethics, 1918 February 15-May (Box 28)
      (Leibnitz. Evils listed. Three attributes: agnostic, theological, ethical. Notes on Origen. St. Augustine. Natural and Moral Ends. The spiritual ideal. Evolution. Perfection. The ontological argument. The idea of organism. The ethical experience. The spiritual relation. Sympathy. Sickness, bereavement, oppression, sin. Irremediable evils. Freedom of will. Transcendental derivation. Student’s Notes - Gutmann, Randall, Rosenbaum, Wikander. )
    - Political Ethics, 1918 October-1919 January (Box 28)
      (Three impulses at work in the war. Cole’s book and Henderson’s program. Transformation of attitude required. Anger and hate. Criticism of Bridges. League of nations. Right of secession. National self-determination. Treitschke. Hegel. Aristotle’s conception of Freedom. St. Augustine. Rousseau. Campbell’s “Greek Religion”. The State in “The Ethical Philosophy of Life.”)
    - Social Ethics (1), Undated (Box 29)
      (Remuneration of services. Schmoller. The church and the labor question. Relation of the State to economic progress.)
    - Social Ethics (2), Undated (Box 29)
      (Socialism. (Ethics of Renumeration. Organization of Industries. “Das Kapital.”) )
    - Miscellaneous Course Notes, Undated (Box 29)
      (Doctrine of the soul., Does the world owe you a living? Economic justice. Equality of opportunity. Ethical ideal. Ethical theory. Ethics. Ethics - Notes. Henry Adams. Incongruities or paradoxes in human existence, Justice. Memoranda for University lectures. Newark boycott. Originality and discipleship. Political liberty. Popular self-government. Property. Relations of manufacturing and agriculture. Representation. Rights of the individual. The social sense. Sovereignty. Spiritual ideal. Spinoza. Unitary personality. The witness to moral personality in recovery from sin. Worth vs: value. The wounded self-consciousness of the wealthy.)
    - Miscellaneous Lectures (Box 29)
      (Philosophy Club. Meetings of the Philosophical Club, 1901, 1915, 1917, 1924 Notes for the Philosophy Club: the meaning of culture.)
    - Miscellaneous Lectures (Box 29)
      (English Club. Notes for a talk: The technique of expression in English.)
    - Miscellaneous Lectures, 1916 March 9 (Box 29)
      (Teachers College Lecture)
  - Subseries II.2. General Classification (200)
    The General Classification for 200-225 is as follows:
    200 Dr. Adler
    201 Ethical Society (Ethical Culture, or Ethical Involvement)
    201.01 Leadership
    201.02 Ceremonies
    201.03 Glenmore Conferences
    202 Groups in the Ethical Society
    203 Ethical Education
    203.01 Adult Moral Education
    203.02 Discipline
    203.03 Culture (For Oxford Lectures on Culture, see 602)
    203.04 Psychology
    203.05 Berlin Lectures (memo)
    203.06 Education (miscellaneous)
    204 Ethical School
    204a Addresses to
    204.01 High School
    204.02 Pre-Professional School
    204.02 Business School
    204.03 History Teaching
    204.04 Ethics Teaching – Sunday School – Moral Instruction of Children
    204.05 English Teaching – Studies in English
    204.06 Ethics Lessons
    204.07 School Festivals
    204.08 Ethical Manual or Vade Mecum
    204.09 Addresses to Teachers – Round Table Talks with Teachers
    205 Letters
    206 Conversations
    207 Conferences with Leaders
    208 Bible
    -Old Testament
    -New Testament
    208.01 Reinterpretations
    209 Philosophy
    -Dr. Adler’s Philosophy
    -Educational Philosophy
    General
    209.01 Kant
    209.02 German Philosophy – Hagel
    209.03 John Stuart Mill
    209.04 Hobbes (Lebiathan)
    209.04 English and American
    209.05 Ethical Theory
    209.06 Plato
    209.07 Green’s Prolegomena
    209.08 Evolution
    209.10 Philosophy Club Notes
    210 Theology and Theologians
    -Martin Luther
    -Saint Augustine
    210.01 Catholic Church
    210.02 Miscellaneous
    210.03 Christian subjects
    210.04 Ibn Pahya
    210.05 Ethical Religion (address notes)
    210.06 Religion – general
    210.07 Non-Christian Reglions
    211 Greek and Roman Classics
    212 Miscellaneous
    -Embroiderers of Vosges and Building Societies
    -Commerce
    -The Standard
    -Foreign Language Studies
    213 Biographical (On Others)
    -Thomas Carlyle
    -Rousseau
    -Biographical Notes (various)
    -Matthew Arnold
    -Emerson
    213.01 Character studies (polarities or inconcinnities)
    214 Jewish Subjects
    215 Poets and Poetry
    215.01 Dante
    215.02 Shakespeare
    215.03 Goethe
    216 Jottings
    216.01 Reflections
    217 Books (Notes On)
    217.01 Goit “The Soul of American” &c.
    218 Morality and Ethics
    -Individual Ethics
    -Ethico-Religious topics
    -Public and Private Morality
    -Ethical Definitions
    -Ethics (Miscellaneous Notes)
    218.01 Personal Reflections
    218.02 Death, Suicide, Consolations, Immortality
    218.03 Woman, Love, Feminism, etc.
    218.03 Marriage and Divorce
    218.03 Womanhood, the Social Evil, Family
    218.03 Talks to Women
    218.04 Imperfect Relations
    219 Religion
    -Religious Topics Discussed
    -Concerning Spirituality
    -Religious Topics (continued)
    -Religious Books
    -Symbolism, Mysticism, etc.
    -The Idea of God
    -The Soul and Body of a Religion
    220 Politics
    -Political Ethics Circle, 1897-1900
    -American Politics
    -Politics (General)
    220.01 The World War
    220.01 War and Peace
    220.01 Political Subjects
    220.01 The Philippines
    220.01 Municipal Politics – Democracy
    220.01 Political Questions
    221 Sociology and Economics
    -Webb’s “Industrial Democracy”
    -Economics
    -Property
    -Stammler “Wirtschaft und Recht”
    -Labor and Social Problems
    -Labor
    -Social Science, Social Law (Berth)
    -Sociology
    -Socialism, Property, Social Reform
    -Social topics (Miscellaneous)
    -Social Settlements
    -Social Topics (continued)
    -The Negro Problem
    -Social Institutions
    -Child Labor
    -Progress
    -Housing in all countries
    221a National Types
    221a Ostrogorski (America)
    222 History – Miscellaneous Notes on
    223 Law – Miscellaneous Notes on
    224 Science – Notes relating to Science
    225 Art and Aesthetics – Music and Dancing
    The name index for the 200 classification is arranged by name, followed by the classification number, and the folder number within that classification number. The index has been converted from an older document; in some cases the numbers were unclear on the original. The index is as follows:
    Abbot of Cluny 213.01--4
    Abelard 213.01--1
    Abraham 208--1a
    Adler, Henry 213--3
    Adler, Dr. Felix 200--1 to 8
    Adler, Mrs. Frida 201.02--2
    Adler, Dr. Isaac 213.01--1, 7
    Adler, Mrs. Isaac 201.02--2
    Aeschuylus 211--3
    Agricola 211--1
    Alexander the Great 213.01--1, 6
    Allen 224--1
    Altamira 222--1
    A1thusius 212.01--1
    A1tschul- 201.02--2c
    Amos 208--1b
    Angell-203.04--1
    Anselm, Saint 210.2--3
    Antigone 211--2
    Aquinas 210.02--3
    Ariel 217--1
    Aristophanes 211--3
    Aristotle- 209.03--1, 2 and 225--1
    Armstrong 213.01--6
    Arnet 206--1
    Arnold, Matthew 213--4
    Arrhenius 224--1
    Athanasius 213.01--1
    Atkins 206--2
    Augustine, Saint 203---8 and 210--2
    Augustus Caesar 213.01--1
    B., Irma 201.02--2c
    B.L.D. 206--2
    Bacon, Francis 217--3
    Bagehot 220--3
    Baker, Ray S. 206--1
    Bakewell 206--2
    Baillie 213.01--9
    Baldwin 201.03--3a
    Baldwin 221--6
    Baldwin, W.H. 201.03--2
    Balfour 220.01--l
    Ballin 213--3
    Barras 219--3a and 217--3
    Barc1ay 209.04--3
    Barnes, Earl 213.01--8
    Barrows 206--2
    Barth 221--5
    Bayard 213.01--6
    Bebel 218.03--3
    Bergson 209.08--1
    Berlioz 213.01-- 1
    Bernard (Saint) 213.01--1
    Bernstorff 217--1
    Bertrand, L. 210--2
    Bewer 208--1
    Binge 201.02--2a
    Bishop 213.03---2
    Bismarck 213.01---9
    Bitter 201.02--2a
    Black 201.01--3
    Blaine 220--2
    Bloch 201--1
    Blumenthal 201.02--2a
    Bodin 213.01---1
    Boehme, Jacob 213 .01--1
    Boemke, Dr. 206--2
    Boethius 211--1
    Bonaventura 210.01--1
    Booth 221--4a
    Posuet 217--1
    Bourget 217--3
    Bradley 215.02--1 and 221--9a
    Brailsford 217--2 and 220.01--5
    Brandeis 206--1
    Brehn 203.04--1
    Brentano 221--4a
    Bridges 201--6 and 205--1
    Brill 201.02--3
    Brooks, Philipps 213--3
    Browne 217--3
    Bruce 203--2
    Browning 213.01--4
    Bruere 206--4
    Bruno 213.01--1
    Bryce 220.01--1, 4 and 222--2
    Buddha 210.06--1a, 1b, and 213.01---9
    Burgess 223--1 and 222--2
    Burkhardt 222-3
    Burke 213.01--6
    Burnham 203.04--1
    Burr 219--3a
    Buschman 209--1
    Bussey 209.05--1
    Butler 201.02--3, 203.06--2, 205--1, and 205--2
    Byron 213--3
    C. 201.02--2a
    Caesar 211--2 and 213.01--1
    Calderon 217--1
    Calpurnia 211--2
    Calvin 210.03--2 and 217--3
    Campanella 213.01--1
    Canning 213.01--8
    Cardozo 223--1
    Carlyle 204.05--2, 213--1, and 213.01--3,4,5
    Catherine of Sienna 213.01--5
    Catherine the Great 213.01--5
    Cato the Edler 213.01--7
    Cervantes 217--3
    Chapin 206--1
    Chapman 211-1
    Chatham 213.01--6
    Cheyney 222--2
    Christopher 205--1
    Chrysostom 213.01--3
    Chubb 205--1 and 206--1
    Cicero 211--3
    Clemenceau 213.01--3
    Cohen 209.05--1
    Cohen 209-02--1
    Cohen 209--3b
    Cohen, Barbara 201.02--2a
    Cohen, Bernard 201.02--2a
    Cohen, Julius H. 205--1
    Cohn 218.03--1
    Coit Stanton 205--1,2 and 217.01--1
    Coleridge 217--3
    Columbus 213.01--3
    Comte 209--3a
    Constantine 213.01--3
    Copernicus 213.01--1
    Cossar 221--2a
    Cranmer 213.01--1
    Croft 212--4
    Crompton 221--4
    Cromwell 213--1,3 and 213.01--1
    Crutwell 211--2
    Cumberland 217--3
    Cybeline 215.02--1
    Cyril of Alexandria 213.01--3
    Da Feltre 213.01--2
    Damien, Father 210.02--2
    Daniels, Dr. 206--2
    Dante 209.04--3 and 209.08--1
    David 208--1a
    Davidson 201.02--2a
    Davidson, Mrs. 201.02--2c
    Davies 202--6 and 222--4
    Day 212--2
    Deland, Mrs. M. 205--1
    De La Saussays 210.06--1a
    De Medici (See Medici)
    Demeter 211--2
    Demosthenes 213.01--3
    Dennis 210.03--1
    Descartes 209--3b and 213.01--6
    Dewey 203.05--1, 203.04--1, and 209.05--1
    Dickinson 223--1
    Dominicans 210.01--1
    Donai 201.02--2a
    Donatello 213.01--2
    Donne 217--2
    Drew 206--4
    Drummond 205--2
    Dubois 221--10
    Dubnow 214--2
    Duncker 210.06--1a
    Dunning 210.02--3
    Durkheim 210--3a
    Duveneck 205--8
    Earnshaw 205--1
    Edwards 217--4
    Eggleston 204.03--2
    Einstein 209.08--1
    Eisler 209.02--1a
    Eliot, George 213-01--4 and 217--1
    Elliott, Dr. 201.02--2a, 205--1, 206--1, 206--4, and 207--1
    Ellesburgh, Dr. 201.02--2c
    Emerson, Huntington 204.02--1a
    Emerson, Ralph Waldo 204.02--1a and 213--5
    Enelow 214--1
    Epictetus 209--3b
    Epicurus 211---2
    Erasmus 213.01--5
    Erdmen 209-06--1
    Euripides 211--3
    Ewald 217--1
    Farrington 203.04--1
    Fecher 205--2
    Fichte 203.06--2 and 209.02--1
    Fiske 222--2
    Flexner 218.03--3
    Fosdick 210.03--2 and 210.02--1
    Fouche 213.01--2
    Fouillee 203--1b and 221a--1
    Fra Angelico 213.01--2
    Francis de Sales (Saint) 213.01--5
    Francis of Assisi (Saint) 213.01--5
    Franciscans 210.01--1
    Frankenheimer 210.02---2
    Franklin 201.07--1
    Frederick the Great 213.01--9
    Freeman 222--1
    Freund 223--2
    Friedel 217--4 and 209.02--1a
    Friedlaender, Dr. 206--4 and 211--1
    Friess, Dr. H. 206--1,2,3 and 207--1
    Frothingham 213.01--7
    Froude 211--2
    Fuller 217--4
    Fullerton, Prof. 206--2 and 209--3a
    Gailey 205--1
    Galileo 213--3 and 213.01--6,8,9
    Geiger 213.01--3
    Gensonne 213.01--6
    Gerhard 213.01--3
    Gibbins 222--2
    Gandhi 213.01--8
    George, Henry 221--2b
    Ghent 221--8
    Giddings 221--6
    Gibbon 213.01--2
    Gibbons 222--2
    Giércke 209.02--1a and 220--3
    Giffen 221--4a
    Gill 213.01---8
    Ginsberg 214--1
    Gladstone 213.01--4
    Goethe 213.1--3,9 and 215.03--1
    Golding 201.06--1, 206--2, and 213.01--7
    Goode 220.01--5
    Goodnow 220-01--4
    Grady 201.02--3
    Grant, Percy 218.03--2
    Greene, Col. 205--2
    Greene 222--3
    Grim, J. 218--1
    Guggenheim 206--4
    Gutmann, James 205--1,2 and 206--2
    Guyau 217--2
    H. Miss 204.04--1c
    H. Miss Barbara 201.02--2a
    H.S. 213.01--9
    Hadley 221--2b
    Hall 203.04--1
    Hamilton 209.04--3
    Hamlet 215.02--1
    Hanslich 225--3
    Harnack 209.02--1 and 210--2
    Harris 203.06--2
    Hart 203.04--1,3 and 222--2
    Hart, James H. 205.01
    Harte, Bret 213.01--1
    Hartmann 217--4
    Hashimoto, K. 205--1
    Hauf 217--1
    Haven 213.01--9
    Hawthorne 217--4
    Hayes 217--2
    Hayes, Pres. 213.01--8
    Hearn, L. 210.06--1a
    Hegel 200.02--1,2 and 209.04--3
    Henley 213.02--1a
    Henry VIII 213.01--1
    Herbart 209--3b
    Herodotus 211--3
    Herzog 210.02--3
    Hildebrand 201.01--2
    Hill 201.02--2a and 218--5b
    Hillquit 213.01--7
    Hirsch, Emil 218-02--1a
    Hirsch, Robert 201.02--2a and 201.07--1
    Hobbes 209.04--2
    Hoeffding 209--3b and 209.02--1
    Homer 211--2
    Hoover 213.01--7
    Hopper 206--2
    Hosea 208--1
    Huber 210.01--1
    Hume 209.04--3
    Humphrey 205--2
    Hu Su 213.01--7
    Huxley 209.08--1, 213.01--6, and 224--1
    Hynd 205--1
    Hyslop 209.05--3
    Ibn Pahya 210.04--1
    Ibsen 213.01--4
    Inge 210.02--3
    Iphigenia 211--3
    Ireland 217--4
    Isaiah 208--1 and 208--1b
    Islam 210.06--1a, 1b
    Isocrates 211--2
    Israel 214--3,4
    Ivan the Terrible 213.01--2
    Jablonower 206--1
    James, William 209.04--3 and 210.06--1
    Jastrow 210.02--2a, 210.06--1, 210.06--1a, 214--2, and 219--2
    Jefferson 212.01--6
    Jeremiah 208--1, 1a
    Jerome, Saint 213.01--5
    Jesuits 210.01--1, 2
    Jesus 208--2a, 208.01--1, 210.03--2, and 214--1,2
    Jevons 221--2b
    Joan of Arc 213.01--8
    Job 208--1, 1a
    Jodl 201--7
    Johnson, Alvin S. 206--2
    Johnson 213.01--1 and 218.03--3
    Johnson, Samuel 213.01--2
    Johnston 220---2
    Jonas, Ruth 205--1
    Jonasson 201.02--2a
    Judaism 214--4
    Julian 213.01--3
    Jung 203.04--3
    K. (the case of) 213.01--8
    Kallinos 211--2
    Kant 209--3a, 209.01--1, 209.02--1, 1a
    Kaufman, C. 201.02--2a
    Kautsky 210.03--1
    Keats 215.1
    Kempis, Thomas A. 210.01--a,2
    Kennedy 205--1
    Kepler 213.01--1, 6, 8
    Ketcham 210.06--1b
    Keyser 210.06--1b
    Kidd 209.08--1
    King, Ed. 206--4
    King Lear 215.02--1
    Kipling 217--1
    Klaber 201.02--2a
    Knies 221--2, 2a
    Kohn, Mrs. A. 201.02--2c
    Kohn 201.02--2a
    Kohn, Mrs. 201--7
    Kohn, Robert 206--1 and 207--1
    Landor 211--2
    Langlois 204.03--2
    Laotze 210.06--1a
    LaSalle 213.01--2
    Las Casas 231.01--2
    Lawson 201.02--2a
    Lazarus 203.01--1a and 218--5e
    Lee, Miss 201.02--2
    Leibniz 209.02--1
    Leonardo 213.01--3
    Lesinsky 201.02--2a
    Lessing 217--4
    Lezinsky 205--1
    Leuba 203.04--2 and 204.04--1d
    Levy 203.04--2 and 205--2
    Lewis 205--1,2 and 206--4
    Lewissohn 217--1
    Liebman, C. 201.02--2a
    Liebman, J. 201.02--2a
    Liebmann 209.02--1
    Li Hung Chang 213.01--3
    Lincoln 213--3 and 213.01--7
    Lindsay, Dr. 206--3
    Lippman 217--2
    Locke 209.04--3
    Lowenstein 206--4
    Loewenthal 201.02--2a
    Lotze 209.02--1a
    Lowell 220--3
    Lowie 217--4
    Loyola 210.01--1
    Luke, Saint 208--2
    Luther 210--1, 213.01--4, and 212--4
    M. John 213.01--8
    McClellan 203.04--1
    McDaniel 201.02--3
    McTaggart 209.05--3
    Macbeth 205.02--1a
    Machiavelli 213.01--8
    Mackenzie 205--4 and 221--7,8
    Maeterlinck 217--2
    Maimonides 214--2
    Maitland 220.01--5
    Manning 218-03--2 and 213--3
    Marcus Aurelius 209--3b
    Mark, Saint 208--2
    Marshall 221--2a
    Martin Ev. D. 203.04--2
    Marx 217--4
    Matthew 208--2
    Matthews 222--4
    Medici, de 213.01--2
    Maurice 218--1
    Maurois 217--1
    Meierhof 201.02--2b
    Mendelssohn 214--4
    Meyer 222--1
    Michaelangelo 213.01--5
    Michoud 223--1
    Mill, John Stuart 209.04--1 and 213.01--2
    Miller 210.06--1
    Milton 213.01--4, 5, 215--1, and 218.03--2
    Mimnermos 211--3
    Minghetti 221--2a, 4a
    Mirandola 213.01--2
    Mohammed 210.06--1a (see Islam) and 210.06--1a
    Montague 206--1
    Montaigne 213.01--8
    Montefiore 214--3
    Montesquieu 213.01--2
    Monteser, Dr. F. 201.02--2c
    Montgomery 209.04--3
    Moore, Prof. 209.05--2
    Moore, Miss 206--2,4
    Moore 214--4
    Moore’s Pragmatism 209--1a
    Moravians 210.03--1
    More 213.01--1
    Morgenthau 205--2
    Mormonism 210.06--1b
    Moses 208--1a
    Moskowitz 213.01--8
    Moulet 203--1b
    Mox 206--2
    Mueden, Miss 204.07--1
    Muensterberg 203.04--2, 221a--1, and 225--2
    Muirhead 209.04--3
    Munson 213.01--9
    Murphy, Edgar G. 201.02--2
    Muzzey 222--1
    Nachmanides 214--4
    Nahlovksy 203.04--3
    Napoleon 213.01--2,5
    Nason 218.03--1
    Necarsulmer, Mrs. 201.02--2c
    Nero 213.01--3
    Nettleship 209.05--1
    Neuman, D. 201.02--2b
    Neumann, Dr. 203--1a and 205--1
    Newman 210.02--2
    Newton 213--3
    Nicholson 221--4a
    Niederer 205--2
    Nietzsche 209.02--1a and 213.01--5
    Noyes 213.01--9
    O’Dell 206--4
    Oedipus 211--3
    Okuma 210.06--1a
    Oldenberg 210.06--1b
    Openhym 201.02--2b
    Orpheus 211--2
    Origen 210--2
    Ostrogorski 221a--2
    Otto, Prof. 206--4 and 219--8
    P., Mrs. 213.01--7
    Paracelsus 213.01--5
    Parker 225-2
    Pascal 218--5d
    Pasteur 210.01--2
    Pater 217--5 and 209.06--1
    Patten 206--4
    Paul, Saint 208--2, 2a, 208.01--1, and 210.03--1
    Paulsen 209.02--1
    Payton 206--2
    Peabody 205--1
    Pear 217--1
    Pellagius 210--2
    Pericles 211--2, 3
    Perkins 221-11
    Perry 206--1
    Petrarch 213.01--2
    Pfeiffer 201.02--2b
    Pfister 209.02--1
    Pfleiderer 208--2
    Philippe-Egalite 213.01--2
    Philo 214--3
    Pindar 211--3
    Pinner 201.02--2b
    Pischen 210.06--1a
    Plato 209-06--1 and 213.01--9
    Philocletes 211--3
    Pliny 211--2
    Ploss 218.03--1
    Plotinus 210.02--3
    Plutarch 213.01--6 and 211--2
    Pollock 220--3
    Porter 205--2
    Prantl 209.02--1a
    Pritchett 217--5
    Prometheus 211--3
    Pupin 213.01--8
    Pythagoras 213.01--6 and 210.01--1
    R., Dr. 203.04--3
    Rabelais 213--3
    Randall 217--2
    Rashdall 221--7
    Reenan 219--3a
    Rein 203.06--2
    Reinach 225--2
    Renan 213--3, 208--2a, and 213.01--5
    Resse, E.P. 205--1
    Reville 210.06--1a
    Richard III 215-02--1
    Richard 218.03--2
    Richelieu 213.01--1, 5
    Riegelman 205--1
    Riis, Jacob 213.01--8
    Ritley 221--7
    Ritschl 209.02--2b
    Robertson 201.02--2b and 225--2
    Robespierre 213.01--6,9
    Robinson 209.09--1a, 217--2, and 223--1
    Rogers 205--1
    Roland, (Chenson de) 215--1
    Roland Mme. 213.01--6, 9
    Roosevelt 221--8
    Rosenbaum, H. 201.02--2b
    Rosenbaum, Yertha 201.02--2b
    Rosenblatt 205--1
    Rothschild 201.02--2b
    Rousseau 213--2
    Royce 205--1 and 209.05--1
    Russel 220.01--1b
    S. 209.04--3
    S. Edwin 218.02--1
    S. G 201.02--2b
    S. Mrs. 206--2
    S. R (Dr.) 201.02--2, 2c
    Sabatier 210.01--1
    Saitschick 213.01--2
    Saladin 213.01--9
    Salter, Wm. M. 205--1, 2, 213.01--8, 220--3, and 223--1
    Sanderson 222--2
    Santayana 209--3 and 209.04--3
    Sargent 225--3
    Savonarola 213.01--9
    Sax 221--2
    Schainwald, R.H. 201.02--2b
    Schaeffle 221--2a and 221--8
    Schasler 209.02--1
    Schiller 215--1
    Schleisrmacher 209.02--1a
    Schlick 209.02--1
    Schneider 217--5
    Schopenhauer 209.02--1, 1a
    Schreiber 219--3a
    Schurman 220-01--1b and 209.08--1
    Schurz 213--3 and 221--8
    Scopes 209.08--1
    Seebohm 210.02--3
    Seignobos 204.03--2
    Seligman, Miss V. 201.02--2
    Seligman, Prof. 221--7, 9a
    Seligsberg, A. 201.02--2b
    Sellers 209.09--1a
    Sels 219--3a
    Semken, C. 201.02--2c
    Seneca 211--1 and 213.01--3
    Shaftesbury 213.01--8
    Shakespeare 215.02--1
    Sheldon 201--4 and 206--2
    Sidgwick 209.05--1
    Siegfried 217--5
    Sigwart 209.05--1,5 and 209.09--1a
    Simmel 209.02--1a
    Small 203.04--2
    Smith, Adam 221--2b
    Smith, H. 201.03--3, 204.01--1, 206--1, and 207--1
    Smith, Robertson 214--1
    Smith & Wace 210--2
    Snell, Lord 205--1
    Socrates 208--2a
    Sohm 223--1, 2
    Solon 211--2
    Sombart 214--1
    Sophocles 211--3
    Southey 213.01--4
    Spencer 209.05--2
    Spencer, Mrs. 201--7 and 218-03--3
    Spiller 205--2
    Spinoza 209.09--1
    Spofford 204.04--1
    Stammler 221--3, 3a
    Stein, Leo 201.02--2b
    Steinthal 213.01--7
    Stevenson 213.01--8, 215.02--1a, 217--1, and 218.02--1a
    Stewardson 213.01--3
    Stiebel, I. 201.02--3
    Stettheimer 201.02--2b
    Stoics 209--3b
    Strachey 213.01--2
    Strauss, J. 201.02--2b
    Sutherland 209.08--1
    Sutro 201.02--2
    Swedenborg 213.01--5
    Swift 217--1
    Sydney, Sir Philip 213.01--2
    Symonds 222--1
    Tacitus 211--1
    Tagore 206--4 and 213.01--9
    Taoism 210.06--1b
    Tarde 223--2
    Tawney 221--2b
    Taylor, Jeremy 218.02--1a
    Tennyson 218--5f
    Thayer 207--1
    Theresa, Saint 213.04--4
    Thilly 209.05--5
    Thomson 224--1
    Tiberius 213.01--1
    Thomas a Kempis (See Kempis)
    Thurmauer 201.02--2b
    Titchenor 203.04--1
    Tolstoi 225--1
    Tomoyeda 205--2
    Tufts, Prof. 206--4
    Tyrell 210.03--1
    Tyraeos 211-2
    Ueberweg 210--2
    Ulman 201.02--2b
    Ulman, Bernard 201.02--2c
    Unamuno 217--6
    Valero, A.P. 205--1
    Vanderberg 206--4
    Van Loon 222--2
    Varro 211--2
    Vattel 223--2
    Vaughan 212--4
    Veblen 221--7
    Villard 205--2
    Villey 217--1
    Vincent 203.04--2
    Virgil 211--3
    Vittoria Colonna 213.01--5
    Volk, Mrs. D. 201.02--2b
    Von Eicken 218-03--1
    Von Fuelow 222--3
    Von Hartman 218--5a
    Von Huegel 219--3a
    W., Miss 205--2
    Wagner 213.01--5, 213--1, and 221--2
    Waitz 208--3, 219--3a, and 224--1
    Wallace 217--2 and 209.08--1
    Warner 217--1
    Waterman, J. 201.02--2b
    Webb 221--1 and 221--4a
    Weber Co. 221--4b
    Wehle 201.02--2b
    Welle 221--2a
    Wellhausen 214--1, 3 and 208--1a
    Wells 210.06--1b and 219--3a
    Welsh, Jane 213.01--4
    Werner 213.01--5
    Westermarck 218--3
    Westlake 223--1
    Weston 201--4
    White, Pres. 205--1
    Wiener 201-02--2b
    Willoughby 220.03 and 220.01--5
    Wilson, President 205--2, 206--4, and 220--2
    Winckelman 231.01--3
    Wolff 205--1
    Wolsey 213.01--1
    Woodbridge 209-04--3, 221--1, and 209.06--1
    Woodworth 203.04--1
    Wordsworth 215--1
    Worthington 221--4
    Wright 202--6
    Wundt 209.05--1 and 209-05--3
    X. 213.01--3
    Young 205--2
    Yokoi 210.06--1a
    Zeller 209-02--1a
    Zoroaster 210.06--1a
    Zueblin 213.01--8
    - 200 Dr. Adler